

- Ohaka,1216,Bangladesh
- 01684385626
- sacsesumon@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

To be a better human being. Motivated project manager with 8 years of experience in software industry. Interprets and understands key elements of projects to identify adverse trends and take correction action. Applies knowledge of technical aspects, procurement and quality control to successfully execute project plans.

CORE QUALIFICATIONS

- Knowledge of Odoo development
- Problem-solving
- Web application development
- Team Management
- Proposal creation
- Training and development
- Technology integration
- · Analytical problem solving
- · Communication skills
- Technical Skills Python, XML, SQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Git, Odoo Framework, Django Framework, Postgres, MySQL, Bootstrap, Excel
- Tools- PyCharm, PgAdmin, Trello, Jupyter Notebook, Visual Studio Code, MySQL Workbench, Visio, Redmine.
- Power Skills- Creativity, Teamwork, Adaptable, Emotional intelligence, Proposal creation

Shah Alam Sumon

EXPERIENCE

July 2022 - Current

Project Manager BJIT | Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Built collaborative working relationships with project teams.
- Managed client expectations with professional, considered approach to projects.
- Reviewed performance against targets, appropriately identifying and managing risks and opportunities.
- Developed and monitored implementation strategies by creating project schedules and work plans.
- Controlled expenditures by regulating change requests and project activities to decrease overruns and delays.
- Enforced set quality standards to deliver key objectives and project KPIs.
- Communicated progress updates to various stakeholders to secure further funding for project activities.

November 2019 - June 2022

Senior Software Engineer BJIT | Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Designed and developed software enhancements based on penetration results and client feedback.
- Guided, trained and mentored software development engineers in tasks including debugging processes and penetration tests.
- Consulted with stakeholders on project scope to better understand client specifications.
- Developed software by producing clean, efficient code using Python.
- Wrote and developed new and well-tested code for different software projects.
- Contributed to sprint planning, prioritizing backlogs to meet new demands.
- · Resolved redmine tickets with comprehensive bug fixes.
- Developed testable software using agile methodologies to create high-quality deliverables

June 2017 - October 2019

Software Engineer Genweb2 | Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Wrote and developed new and well-tested code for different software projects.
- Gathered requirements from users and wrote definition documents.
- Established rigorous version control framework in GitHub.
- Performed software testing and diagnosis, supporting ongoing embedded system development.
- Contributed to sprint planning, prioritising backlogs to meet new demands.
- Resolved trello tickets with comprehensive bug fixes.
- Communicated changes through Odoo and followed documentation procedures for each fix.
- Investigated requests for maintenance and repairs for swift resolution.
- · Designed and developed software systems using initial brief.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Odoo v15 Functional certified,
 Odoo, Issued Nov 2022
- Modern Big Data Analysis with SQL Specialization, Coursera, Issued Mar 2020
- IBM Data Science Specialization, Coursera, Issued Nov 2019
- Version Control with Git, Coursera, Issued Nov 2019
- AWS Fundamentals: Going Cloud Native, Coursera, Issued Dec 2019

INTERESTS

- Traveling
- · Watching movie and drama
- · Listening music
- · Playing online games
- Food explorer

LANGUAGES Bengali: First Language En: B2 Upper Intermediate hind: A2 Elementary

September 2015 - May 2017

Junior Software Engineer Business Accelerate BD Ltd | Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Skilfully detected and fixed minor bugs on software, completing within deadline dependent situations.
- Regularly researched and learnt codebase to expand knowledge, skills and expertise in software development.
- Wrote and developed new and well-tested code for Odoo projects.
- Established rigorous version control framework in GitHub.
- Evaluated project requirements, identified challenges and proposed alternatives using research and data.

May 2015 - August 2015

Intern BRAC IT Services Limited | Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Entered comments to control system operation, verify functionality and detect errors.
- · Documented actions taken using work order system within ERP.
- · Work on jasper report

October 2013 - December 2013

Intern ADN Telecom Limited | Dhaka, Bangladesh

- · Worked on- Setup and Configure Internet service to the vendors
- · Maintain network services.
- Helped formulate expenditure reports to submit to manager.

EDUCATION

2015

Post Graduate Diploma | ICT

Bangladesh Computer Council, Dhaka, Bangladesh

- · Coursework in software development.
- Soft skill

2013

Bachelor of Science | Computer Science & Engineering, Science Northern University of Bangladesh, Dhaka

2008

HSC | Science

SOS Hermann Gmeiner College, Dhaka

2006

SSC | Science

GenwebredmineSumonSOS Hermann Gmeiner College, Dhaka